No dream is too B.I.G.
Notorious is a music, drama, history film directed by George Tillman Jr..
"Notorious" is the story of Christopher Wallace.
Through raw talent and sheer determination, Wallace transforms himself from Brooklyn street hustler (once
selling crack to pregnant women) to one of the greatest rappers of all time: The Notorious B.I.G.
Follow his meteoric rise to fame and his refusal to succumb to
expectations - redefining our notion of "The American Dream."
Christopher 'Biggie' Wallace, played by Jamal Woolard.
Sean 'Puffy' Combs, played by Derek Luke.
Lil' Kim, played by Naturi Naughton.
Tupac "2Pac" Shakur, played by Anthony Mackie.
Faith Evans, played by Antonique Smith.
Voletta Wallace, played by Angela Bassett.
Notorious is a 2009 American biographical drama film based on the life of Brooklyn-based
hip-hop artist Christopher "Biggie Smalls" Wallace / the Notorious B.I.G..
The film was directed by George Tillman Jr., and written by
Reggie Rock Bythewood and Cheo Hodari Coker.
Jamal Woolard stars as Wallace, with Angela Bassett, Derek
Luke, and Anthony Mackie in supporting roles.
The film dramatizes key events in Biggie's life: his criminal lifestyle, arrest and release from prison, his relationships with Sean Combs (who serves as executive
producer), Tupac Shakur, Lil' Kim, and Faith Evans, his involvement in the East Coast–West Coast hip hop rivalry, and his drive-by-shooting murder on March 9, 1997.
Biggie's mother, Voletta, served as a producer for the film,
alongside his former managers Wayne Barrow and Mark Pitts.
Notorious was released in the United States on January
16, 2009, by Fox Searchlight Pictures.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, with praise mainly aimed at
Woolard's performance and grossed $44.4 million on a $20 million budget.
The film explores themes of rap music, ghetto, murder, death, boom box.
The tone is emotional.